<LanguageData>

    <DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalTitle>Diplomatic Marriage Proposal from {0}</DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalTitle>
    <DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposal>
		Our ally, {0}, proposes a diplomatic marriage with us. The child of our leader, {1}, is to marry one of their important members, {2}.
		\n{2} is waiting outside for our response with some guards. 
		\nIf we accept, the following effects will take place:
		\n1. {1} leaves our colony and joins {0}.
		\n2. {2} accepts our ideology, and will randomly spread it within {0}.
		\n3. Goodwill with {0} immediately maxes out at 100 and decreases daily if below 100, with an increase of {3} per day, influenced by {1}'s social skill.
		\n4. Natural goodwill decay and regular goodwill consumption remain unchanged, but they can quickly recover while the permanent alliance is active.
		\n5. If either party in the marriage dies, the permanent alliance ends.
		\n6. Though goodwill with {0} recovers quickly, if we go too far, the permanent alliance will end!
		\n7. Even after marriage, {1} and {2} will still regularly visit our colony. We need to protect them in order to maintain the permanent alliance.
		\n8. Our leader must always be one of the parents of {1}, passing leadership to someone else will immediately void the permanent alliance.
	</DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposal>
    <DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalAccept>The entire {0} celebrates our union. From now on, we are in a permanent alliance.\n{2} has entered our colony with guards. If {1} is present, they will hold the wedding on the spot before leaving. We must ensure their safety until they leave.</DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalAccept>
    <DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalReject>{0} is disappointed by our rejection. Goodwill has decreased.</DMP_DiplomaticMarriagePlusProposalReject>

	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventFactionConversionTitle>Permanent Alliance Ideology Change</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventFactionConversionTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventFactionConversion>News comes from our allied {0}, from the child of our leader {1} and their spouse {2}, that thanks to their long efforts, our truth is now spreaded throughout {0}, becoming their primary ideology.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventFactionConversion>

	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEndedTitle>Permanent Alliance Ended</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEndedTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_BOTH_DEATH>Due to the deaths of both parties of {1} and {2}, our permanent alliance with {0} has ended.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_BOTH_DEATH>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_PLAYER_BETROTHED_DEATH>Due to the death of our leader's child, {1}, our permanent alliance with {0} has ended.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_PLAYER_BETROTHED_DEATH>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_NPC_MARRIAGE_SEEKER_DEATH>Due to the death of the other party's important member, {2}, our permanent alliance with {0} has ended. {1} will return to our colony soon.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_NPC_MARRIAGE_SEEKER_DEATH>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_DIVORCE>Due to the divorce of {1} and {2}, our permanent alliance with {0} has ended. {1} will return to our colony soon.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_DIVORCE>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_GOODWILL_TOO_LOW>Due to our low goodwill with {0}, our permanent alliance has ended. The deterioration of relations also led to the end of the marriage between {1} and {2}. {1} will return to our colony soon.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_GOODWILL_TOO_LOW>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_FACTION_DEFEATED>Due to the destruction of {0}, the permanent alliance has ended. Unfortunately, both {1} and {2} have died in the war.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_FACTION_DEFEATED>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_PLAYER_LEADER_NOT_PARENT_OF_BETHOTHED>As our leader has been replaced by {3}, who is not the parent of {1}, {0} no longer sees us as a reliable permanent alliance. However, {0} still keep {1} and {2} to continue living among them.</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventAllianceEnded_Reason_INVALID_REASON_PLAYER_LEADER_NOT_PARENT_OF_BETHOTHED>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceVIPUnexpectedFactionWarningTitle>Warning: Wrong Faction Detected for Key Pawn of Diplomatic Marriage</DMP_PermanentAllianceVIPUnexpectedFactionWarningTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceVIPUnexpectedFactionWarning>
		It has been detected that the key pawn {0}, on whom the permanent alliance with {1} depends, does not belong to the supposed allied faction {1}, but instead to the faction {2}, and he/she is not in the temporary stay event. This is unexpected, so their faction has been forcibly corrected.
		\nWarning: During the permanent alliance, unless for the temporary home visit, in no way you should attempt to imprison or recruit anyone of the key couple, whether through the vanilla game, dev mode, or by other mods (such as Hospitality). Doing so may completely break this mod (Diplomatic Marriage and Permanent Alliance)!
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceVIPUnexpectedFactionWarning>

	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanArriveTitle>Help Request from Kin Ally Caravan</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanArriveTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanArrive>
		{0}, this is {1}. {2} and I are in a caravan from {3}, but {4} is attempting to ambush us. They outnumber us, so we had to retreat to your colony for refuge.
		\nThey are coming, please help us!
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanArrive>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyIncomingTitle>Enemy Incoming</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyIncomingTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyIncoming>
		{0}, here they are! Everyone, prepare for battle!
		\n(Note: Our permanent alliance with {3} relies on the marriage of {1} and {2}, so we must protect them at all costs. If either dies in battle, the permanent alliance will end!)
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyIncoming>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyDefeatedTitle>Enemy Defeated</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyDefeatedTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyDefeated>
		Thank you, {0}, for your assistance. We need to rest at your base for a while before continuing our journey. Here's a little gift for you as thanks.
		\nMay the friendship of {1} and {2} last forever!
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVisitCaravanEnemyDefeated>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceWarningVIPOnTheMapTitle>Important pawns in our colony</DMP_PermanentAllianceWarningVIPOnTheMapTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceWarningVIPOnTheMap>
		Attention! {1} and/or {2}, which are the key married couple of our permanent alliance with {0}, just appeared on our colony. We need to ensure their safety.
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceWarningVIPOnTheMap>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayPlanVisitTitle>Nostalgia from permanent ally</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayPlanVisitTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayPlanVisit>
		{1}, after spending so long in {0}, I'm starting to miss home. I'd like to come back for a temporary stay. {0} has agreed to let us leave for a while, and {2} will also accompany me.
		\nWe expect to arrive in about {3} days, and we'll stay for approximately {4} days.
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayPlanVisit>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayArrivalTitle>Married couple arriving</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayArrivalTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayArrival>
		{0}, we have arrived safely. We will temporarily follow your commands during this period.
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayArrival>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayDepartureTitle>Married couple leaving</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayDepartureTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayDeparture>
		{1}, it's time for us to return to {0}. Thank you for your hospitality during this time. See you next time!
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventTemporaryStayDeparture>
	
	<!--Collaborated mod: Rimcities-->
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesAssaultTitle>Permanent ally assaulting city</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesAssaultTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesAssault>
		{0}, this is {1}. We {2} are planning an assault against the large city {4} of our enemy {3}. We need your help.
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesAssault>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesDefenseTitle>Permanent ally city under attack</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesDefenseTitle>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesDefense>
		{0}, this is {1}. Our enemy {3} is sieging our large city {4} of {2}. Please come and help us!
	</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRimcitiesDefense>
	
	<!--Collaborated mod: A Petition For Provisions(APFP)-->
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledNotPA>Request specific items disabled (Not permanent ally)</DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledNotPA>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledInCD>Request specific items disabled (Remaining cooldown:{0} days)</DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledInCD>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledSOS2SpaceMap>Request specific items disabled (Unavailable on SOS2 space map)</DMP_PermanentAllianceAPFPButtonDisabledSOS2SpaceMap>
	
	<!--Collaborated mod: Dynamic Diplomacy-->
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAStartedTitle>Military alliance against us and our PA</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAStartedTitle>
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAStarted>
	Our permanent ally {0} has grown too powerful, alot of factions on the planet has formed a military alliance against them. Because of our union, they also declared war on us! 
	</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAStarted>
	
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEndedTitle>Military alliance ended</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEndedTitle>
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_TOO_WEAK>
	Since our permanent ally {0} is heavily weaken now, the military alliance has been disbanded. But we still need to work hard to restore relationship with them one by one.
	</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_TOO_WEAK>
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_ENDED>
	Since {0} is no longer our permanent ally, all factions (except permanently hostile ones) has ceased hostility against us. But we still need to work hard to restore relationship with them one by one. Besides, the alliance against {0} will still remain for some time.
	</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_ENDED>
	<DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_NO_ENOUGH_FACTIONS>
	Since there are no longer enough factions in the alliance against our permanent ally {0}, the military alliance has been disbanded.
	</DMP_DynamicDiplomacyAllianceAgainstPAEnded_PA_NO_ENOUGH_FACTIONS>
	
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVocabulary_Father>Dad</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVocabulary_Father>
	<DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVocabulary_Mother>Mom</DMP_PermanentAllianceEventRandomVocabulary_Mother>
	
	<!--Settings-->
	<DMP_Setting_ModName>Diplomatic Marriage +</DMP_Setting_ModName>
	<DMP_Setting_GoodwillDailyIncreaseBaseValue>The base value of daily goodwill increase for permanent ally</DMP_Setting_GoodwillDailyIncreaseBaseValue>
	<DMP_Setting_GoodwillDailyIncreaseSocialSkillFactor>The social skill factor multiplier during daily goodwill increase.</DMP_Setting_GoodwillDailyIncreaseSocialSkillFactor>
	<DMP_Setting_ThreatMultiplier>Determines AI army strength in various Mod events, affects both ally and enemies. 1 = 100%</DMP_Setting_ThreatMultiplier>
	<DMP_Setting_FactionConversionChancePerSocialSkill>The daily chance to convert the whole ally faction is increased by this value * the sum of social skills of the couple</DMP_Setting_FactionConversionChancePerSocialSkill>
	<DMP_Setting_WarningVIPOnTheMap>Popup warning letter when the married couple is on the colony map</DMP_Setting_WarningVIPOnTheMap>
	<DMP_Setting_WarningVIPOnTheMapDetails>Although events from this mod already come with warning letters, vanilla and other mods may still randomly spawn the VIP couple as regular pawns of the permanently allied NPC faction. This option will warn you once they are on any of your colony map, whatever the reason, so that you know when you need to protect them. The warning popup maximum once per in-game day.</DMP_Setting_WarningVIPOnTheMapDetails>
	
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayMinimumDaysForNostalgia>Minimum days must pass after the leader's child who left the colony for diplo marriage before they may feel homesickness.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayMinimumDaysForNostalgia>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDailyChanceInitial>After the above interval, the initial daily chance of feeling homesickness.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDailyChanceInitial>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDailyChanceIncrease>Whenever homesickness is possible, how much chance increases each day.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDailyChanceIncrease>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayStartAfterDaysMinimum>After deciding to return for a temporary stay, the minimum time before arrival.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayStartAfterDaysMinimum>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayStartAfterDaysMaximum>The maximum time before arrival. This value must be greater than or equal to the minimum value.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayStartAfterDaysMaximum>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDurationMinimum>The minimum duration (in days) of a temporary stay.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDurationMinimum>
	<DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDurationMaximum>The maximum duration (in days) of a temporary stay. Note: this value must be greater than or equal to the minimum value.</DMP_Setting_TemporaryStayDurationMaximum>
	
	<DMP_Setting_APFPCooldownReductionHoursPerGlobalSettlementPercentage>APFP CD reduction for each 1% of PA global settlement percentage</DMP_Setting_APFPCooldownReductionHoursPerGlobalSettlementPercentage>
	<DMP_Setting_APFPCooldownReductionHoursPerGlobalSettlementPercentageDetails>
	After each APFP (A Petition For Provisions) trade, how many In-Game hours of cooldown reduction for each 1% of global settlement percentage for your permanent ally. This feature is for players having APFP installed at the same time. It changes abit the APFP trade (which is too OP) by making it a privilege exclusively offered by permanent allied faction. It calculates the percentage of number of PA faction settlements over total global settlements, then use it to determine the cooldown time after each APFP trade. This means that the more powerful your PA faction, the more you can benefit from APFP trades. The cooldown time is always between 3 days and 1 year. The player has to wait until being able to request provision from PA faction again. Also APFP trades will always be refused by all factions except your permanent ally (even vanilla allies will no longer do it), If Rimcities is installed, large cites are also counted as settlements. This feature encourages players to help permanent ally to conquer more settlements via mods like Rimcities or others, so that they can benefit more from APFP trades. 
	</DMP_Setting_APFPCooldownReductionHoursPerGlobalSettlementPercentageDetails>
	
	<DMP_Setting_EnableAllianceAgainstPAEvent>Enable global alliance against PA</DMP_Setting_EnableAllianceAgainstPAEvent>
	<DMP_Setting_EnableAllianceAgainstPAEventDetails>When your PA reached a certain percentage of global settlements, other factions may form alliance against them, they will stop war among themselves and start war against your PA and against player as well. No peace can be made during this event (even the player or other mods try to make peace it wont last long). This event require Dynamic Diplomacy to trigger, and in Dynamic Diplomacy the mod config about global alliance needs to be activated. The alliance of this event is counted as an Dynamic Diplomacy alliance as well unless it has no time limit. The alliance ends only when the PA faction becomes weak enough, or PA itself is ended. No other Dynamic Diplomacy alliances can be formed during this event. Besides, whether permanent enemy factions and the Empire will join the alliance depends also on the mod config settings in Dynamic Diplomacy (This mod reads the mod config of Dynamic Diplomacy). 
	</DMP_Setting_EnableAllianceAgainstPAEventDetails>
</LanguageData>
